<resources>
    <string name="app_name">English Essay For Students</string>


    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Webspherex Inc</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_thecow">Thecow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__cow">The_Cow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_tiger">The_tiger</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__lion">The_Lion</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__crow">The Crow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__dog">The Dog</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__bullock">The Bullock</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bottle">Bottle Feeding Kittens</string>
    <string name="title_activity_how">How to start an animal resource or other nonprofit animal
        organization
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_reason">Reasons to adopt a pet</string>
    <string name="title_activity_teacup">Teacup pigs</string>
    <string name="title_activity_intro">Introducing dog to each other</string>
    <string name="title_activity_howto">How to start an animals sanctuary</string>
    <string name="title_activity_injured">Injured Bird</string>
    <string name="title_activity_taking">Taking action for animals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_howtowrite">Howtowrite</string>
    <string name="title_activity_write">" How to write a persuasive paper"</string>
    <string name="introduction_essay_on_cow_cow_is_one_of_the_sacred_animals_of_india_domesticated_in_many_indian_homes_especially_in_villages_it_is_a_major_food_source_in_india_the_milk_of_the_cow_is_used_to_make_various_food_items_including_milk_sweets_paneer_butter_ghee_curd_and_other_sweet_dishes_it_is_referred_as_mother_by_the_hindu_community_of_india_and_people_call_her_gau_mata_characteristics_cows_are_not_very_difficult_from_other_animals_in_appearance_they_have_four_legs_two_ears_two_eyes_one_nose_a_long_tail_and_a_big_body_they_are_available_in_various_breeds_viz_shaiwal_gir_nimari_nagori_bachaur_mewati_etc_they_are_of_several_colours_shape_and_size_they_give_milk_two_times_a_day_except_for_some_who_offer_milk_three_times_a_day_they_consume_grass_hay_fodder_and_chaff_when_there_is_no_grass_available_the_cows_live_on_straw_and_gram_cows_eating_process_is_very_different_they_don_t_chew_the_food_immediately_as_they_get_them_in_the_mouth_they_swallow_the_food_then_sit_down_and_they_recall_the_food_in_the_mouth_and_chew_it_up_cows_milk_cow_milk_is_used_for_anointment_in_temples_by_the_hindus_cows_milk_is_enriched_with_vitamin_a_vitamin_b6_vitamin_b12_vitamin_d_essential_minerals_and_calcium_the_calcium_content_and_minerals_in_the_cow_milk_add_up_to_the_bone_density_and_the_protein_requirement_it_helps_to_maintain_metabolism_and_balance_the_sugar_level_in_the_human_body_the_milk_is_blessed_to_cure_diabetes_and_improve_heart_health_the_milk_contains_omega_3_fat_and_omega_3_fatty_acids_are_a_good_form_of_cholesterol_in_the_body_it_is_also_capable_of_curing_cancer_and_coronary_heart_diseases_children_hate_drinking_milk_and_parents_insist_on_feeding_them_milk_because_it_contains_the_right_amount_of_protein_regular_consumption_of_milk_promotes_natural_growth_of_the_body_adds_immunity_and_renders_energy_that_children_need_in_early_age_the_natural_energy_drink_boosts_physical_and_mental_strength_and_kills_chronic_illness_cows_urine_gau_mutra_hindus_consider_cows_urine_holy_and_it_has_a_special_significance_as_a_medical_drink_it_is_believed_that_sprinkling_cow_s_urine_can_cleanse_one_spiritually_ayurved_claims_gau_mutra_to_be_a_great_curing_agent_in_ayurved_it_believed_that_gau_mutra_possesses_the_ability_to_cure_life_taking_diseases_like_cancer_tb_and_leprosy_a_mixture_of_cow_s_urine_triphala_and_cow_s_milk_can_heal_anaemia_many_countries_like_nigeria_myanmar_use_cow_s_urine_for_medicinal_purposes_too_the_cow_urine_is_also_used_as_a_disinfectant_for_floor_cleaning_it_is_also_used_as_manure_for_production_of_rice_a_fertilizer_is_made_from_a_mixture_of_jaggery_cow_dung_pulse_flour_cow_urine_and_rhizosphere_soil_a_biopesticide_is_made_by_boiling_a_mixture_of_custard_apple_leaves_neem_leaves_and_cow_pee_read_also_health_is_wealth_origin_meaning_explanation_examples_essay_speech_cow_dung_gobar_women_in_indian_villages_make_dung_cake_by_patting_the_cow_dung_on_the_walls_the_dunk_cakes_are_later_used_as_fuels_for_cooking_cow_dung_is_considered_very_pure_which_is_why_indians_in_village_wipe_their_house_with_cow_dung_it_is_also_one_of_the_best_forms_of_natural_fertilizer_the_dung_is_applied_for_soil_enrichment_as_an_age_old_agricultural_practice_but_the_practice_is_lost_with_the_introduction_of_artificial_pesticides_and_chemical_fertilizers_conclusion_the_cow_has_manifold_benefits_for_the_humans_but_there_have_been_numerous_debates_regarding_the_consumption_of_cow_milk_cow_urine_and_application_of_cow_dung_but_whatever_may_be_the_reason_for_the_debate_the_truth_is_that_cow_has_been_beneficial_for_ages_it_will_always_be_there_for_the_cause">Introduction (Essay on Cow)---------------------------------------- Cow is one of the sacred animals of India domesticated in many Indian homes especially in villages. It is a major food source in India. The milk of the cow is used to make various food items including milk sweets, paneer, butter, ghee, curd and other sweet dishes.It is referred as Mother by the Hindu community of India and people call her ‘Gau Mata’. Characteristics---------------------------------------------------------------- Cows are not very difficult from other animals in appearance. They have four legs, two ears, two eyes, one nose, a long tail and a big body. They are available in various breeds viz. Shaiwal, Gir, Nimari, Nagori, Bachaur, Mewati etc. They are of several colours, shape and size. They give milk two times a day except for some who offer milk three times a day. They consume grass, hay, fodder and chaff. When there is no grass available the cows live on straw and gram. Cows’ eating process is very different. They don’t chew the food immediately as they get them in the mouth. They swallow the food then sit down and they recall the food in the mouth and chew it up. -------Cows’ milk-------------------------------------------- Cow milk is used for anointment in temples by the Hindus. Cows’ milk is enriched with vitamin A, vitamin B6, vitamin B12, vitamin D, essential minerals and Calcium. The calcium content and minerals in the cow milk add up to the bone density and the protein requirement. It helps to maintain metabolism and balance the sugar level in the human body. The milk is blessed to cure diabetes and improve heart health. The milk contains Omega-3 fat and Omega-3 fatty acids are a good form of cholesterol in the body. It is also capable of curing cancer and coronary heart diseases. Children hate drinking milk and parents insist on feeding them milk because it contains the right amount of protein. Regular consumption of milk promotes natural growth of the body, adds immunity and renders energy that children need in early age. The natural energy drink boosts physical and mental strength and kills chronic illness. ------------Cows’ urine (Gau Mutra)----------------------- Hindus consider cows’ urine holy and it has a special significance as a medical drink. It is believed that sprinkling cow’s urine can cleanse one spiritually. Ayurved claims Gau Mutra to be a great curing agent. In Ayurved, it believed that Gau Mutra possesses the ability to cure life taking diseases like cancer, TB and leprosy. A mixture of cow’s urine, Triphala and cow’s milk can heal Anaemia. Many countries like Nigeria, Myanmar use cow’s urine for medicinal purposes too. The cow urine is also used as a disinfectant for floor cleaning. It is also used as manure for production of rice. A fertilizer is made from a mixture of jaggery, cow dung, pulse flour, cow urine and rhizosphere soil. A biopesticide is made by boiling a mixture of custard apple leaves, neem leaves and cow pee. Read also: Health is Wealth: Origin, Meaning, Explanation, Examples (Essay,Speech) Cow dung (Gobar)--------------------------------------- Women in Indian villages make dung cake by patting the cow dung on the walls. The dunk cakes are later used as fuels for cooking. Cow dung is considered very pure which is why Indians in village wipe their house with cow dung. It is also one of the best forms of natural fertilizer. The dung is applied for soil enrichment as an age-old agricultural practice. But the practice is lost with the introduction of artificial pesticides and chemical fertilizers. --------------Conclusion ----------------------------------------------- The cow has manifold benefits for the humans but there have been numerous debates regarding the consumption of cow milk, cow urine and application of cow dung. But whatever may be the reason for the debate the truth is that cow has been beneficial for ages it will always be there for the cause.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_studentlife">Student Life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hostellife">Hostel Life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_discipline">Discipline in student life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_studentandolan">Student Andolan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_studentpoli">Student and politics</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rules">Rules in studeent life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_healthinst">Health in student life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_goodst">Good Student</string>
    <string name="title_activity_student_union">Student Union</string>
    <string name="title_activity_struggle">Struggle in student life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_success">Success in student life</string>
    <string name="title_activity_telivision">Telivision</string>
    <string name="title_activity_computer">Computer</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_modern">Modern Science</string>
    <string name="title_activity_radio">Radio</string>
    <string name="title_activity_solar">Solar Energy</string>
    <string name="title_activity_space">Space Travel</string>
    <string name="title_activity_astronaut">Astronaut</string>
    <string name="title_activity_heat">Heat Energy</string>
    <string name="title_activity_internet">Internet</string>
    <string name="title_activity_benefits">Benefits Of Science</string>
    <string name="title_activity_thefarmer">The Farmer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_organicf">Organic Farming</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pisciculture">Pisciculture Or Fish Farming</string>
    <string name="title_activity_horticulture">Horticulture</string>
    <string name="title_activity_poultryfarming">Poultry Farming</string>
    <string name="title_activity_agriculture">Agriculture And It\'s Significance-Economics
        Discussion
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_pesticides">Pesticides</string>
    <string name="title_activity_greenrevolution">Green Revolution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_roleoffarmer">Role Of Farmer In Indian Economy</string>
    <string name="title_activity_autobiography">Autobiography Of A Farmer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_environment">Environment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_enviropollu">Environment Pollution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_airpollution">Air Pollution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_waterpollution">water Pollution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_soilpollution">Soil Pollution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_earth">Earth</string>
    <string name="title_activity_nature">Nature</string>
    <string name="title_activity_earthpollution">Earth Pollution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_biosphere">Biosphere</string>
    <string name="title_activity_globalwarming">Global Warming</string>
    <string name="title_activity_socialmedia">Social Media</string>
    <string name="title_activity_whatsapp">Whats App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_instagram">Instagram</string>
    <string name="title_activity_twitter">Twitter</string>
    <string name="title_activity_facebook">Facebook</string>
    <string name="title_activity_google">Google</string>
    <string name="title_activity_yahoo">Yahoo</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube">YouTube</string>
    <string name="title_activity_email">Email</string>
    <string name="title_activity_independenceday">Independence Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_republicday">Republic Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gandhijayanti">Gandhi Jayanti</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldhindiday">World Hindi Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_armyday">Army Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_valentineday">valentine Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_nationalscienceday">National Science Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldtbday">World TB Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldhealthday">World Health Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_earthday">Earth Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_nationalpanchayatiday">National Panchayati Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mothersday">Mother\'s Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldredcrossday">World Red Cross Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fathersday">Father\'s Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_engineersday">Engineer\'s Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldheartday">World Heart Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldaidsday">World AIDS Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_humanrightsday">Human Rights Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_christmasday">Christmas Day</string>
    <string name="title_activity_diwali">Diwali</string>
    <string name="title_activity_holi">Holi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dussehra">Dussehra</string>
    <string name="title_activity_durgapuja">Durga Puja</string>
    <string name="title_activity_janmashtami">Janmashtami</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ganeshchaturthi">Ganesh Chaturthi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gurupurab">Gurupurab</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rakshabandhan">Rakshabandhan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_eidulfitr">Eid Ul Fitr</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bihu">Bihu</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hemis">Hemis</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pongal">Pongal</string>
    <string name="title_activity_christmas">Christmas</string>
    <string name="title_activity_easter">Easter</string>
    <string name="title_activity_baisakhi">Baisakhi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_searchfrweb">Searchfrweb</string>
    <string name="title_activity_business">Business</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cottageindustry">Cottage Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lightindustry">Light Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_manufacturing">Manufacturing</string>
    <string name="title_activity_timberindustry">Timber Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pharmaceuticalindustry">Pharmaceutical Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_softwareindustry">Software Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_technologyindustry">Technology Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_realestateindustry">Real Estate Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_filmindustry">Film Industry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_worldwidewave">World Wide Wave</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mining">Mining</string>
    <string name="title_activity_industryrevolution">Industry Revolution</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mahatmagandhi">Mahatma Gandhi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_subhashchandrabose">Subhash Chandra Bose</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chandrashekharazad">Chandra Shekhar Azad</string>
    <string name="title_activity_jawaharlalnehru">Jawahar Lal Nehru</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ranilakshmibai">Rani Lakshmi Bai</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dr_rajendraprasad">Dr.Rajendra Prasad</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sardarvallabhaipatel">Sardar Vallabhai Patel</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mangalpandey">Mangal Pandey</string>
    <string name="title_activity_drbabasahebambedkar">Dr.Babasaheb Ambedkar</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sarojininaidu">Sarojin Naidu</string>
    <string name="title_activity_tantiatope">Tantia Tope</string>
    <string name="title_activity_udhamsingh">Udham Singh</string>
    <string name="title_activity_balgangadhartilak">Bal Gangadhar Tilak</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sukhdev">Sukhdev</string>
    <string name="title_activity_anniebesant">Annie Besant</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dadabhainaoroji">Dadabhai Naoroji</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bipinchandrapal">Bipin Chandra Pal</string>
    <string name="title_activity_kmmunshi">K .M Munshi</string>
    <string name="admob_interstitial_id">ca-app-pub-9470171691477952/8233428064</string>
    <string name="admob_interstitial2_id">ca-app-pub-9470171691477952/4675562676</string>

</resources>
